Guide to the Charles Hamm Recordings, 1857-1999 HAMM.2005
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Irving Berlin Research, 2
  - Newspaper Clippings: Song Performances, 1911-1912; 18
    Photocopy of an untitled article in Variety, December 2, year unknown. Photocopy of "Mike Bernard and Amy Butler," in Variety, December 30, 1911. Photocopy of "Jean Alwya," April 15, 1912, source unknown. Photocopy of "American Roof," in Variety, December 9, 1911. Photocopy of "New Acts in "Pop" Houses," November 18, 1911, source unknown. Photocopy of "Vanity Fair," in Variety, November 11, 1911. Photocopy of "Before Christmas at Fifth Avenue to Have…," December 9, 1911, source unknown.
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles: Alexander's Ragtime Band, 1911-1983; 19
    Photocopy of "Alexander's Musical History," by Jim Walsh, in Favorite Pioneer Recording Artists. Photocopy of "Aide Overton Walker and Co," in Variety, July 22, 1911. Photocopy of "The Trocaderos," in Variety, August 19, year unknown. Photocopy of "Correspondence with Chicago," in Variety, April 29, year unknown. Photocopy of "Correspondence with Chicago," in Variety, April 22, 1911. Photocopy of "Adele Oswald," in Variety, September 2, year unknown, pg 21. Photocopy of "Lewis and Pearson," in Variety, August 5, year unknown. Photocopy of "Colonial," in Variety, September 23, year unknown. Photocopy of "Nace Murray and Girls," in Variety, September 23, year unknown. Photocopy of "Kajiyama," in Variety, date unknown. Photocopy of an advertisement "American Music Hall" in Variety, April 16, 1911. Photocopy of an advertisement "Grand Opera House Tonight" in Variety, April 23, 1911. Photocopy of "Hammerstein's Roof," in Variety, August 26, year unknown. Photocopy of "The German Theater," in Variety, April 16, 1911. Photocopy of advertisement clippings, undated. Photocopy of "Green, McHendry and Dean," in Variety, October 7, 1911. Photocopy of "Lyric Trio," in Variety, September 2, year unknown, pg 21. Photocopy of "Colonial," in Variety, September 30, year unknown, pg 23. Photocopy of "Adele Oswald," in Variety, July 1, 1911, pg 16. Photocopy of "George Fox," in Variety, December 2, 1911, pg 19. Photocopy of "Evelyn Ware," in Variety, October 14, year unknown, pg 18.
  - Newspaper Clippings: Performance Practice, 1911-1912; 20
    Photocopy of "Published Songs," in Variety, December 20, 1912. Photocopy of "Blossom Seeley," in Variety, June 24, 1911. Photocopy of "Ann Lorraine," in Variety, July 29, 1911. Photocopy of "Buelah Dallas," May 6, year and source unknown. Photocopy of "New Acts Next Week," December 9, 1911, source unknown. Photocopy of "No Roof Orchestra," November 11, year and source unknown.
  - Newspaper Clippings: Contemporary Issues, 1910-1913; 21
    Photocopy of "The Jew on the Stage" in Variety, December 10, 1910. Photocopy of "Favors Hebrew Acts" in Variety, August 26, 1910. Photocopy of "Switzer and Delaney. Rathskellar Duo," August 26, 1911. Photocopy of "Ragtime versus Classical" in Variety, December 23, 1911. Photocopy of "Great Composers Get Little; Popular Writers Well Paid" in Variety, September 9, 1911. Photocopy of "Suggestive Songs Ordered out of Keith's, Boston" in Variety, June 27, 1913. Photocopy of "Reformer at it Again" in Variety, April 22, year unknown. Photocopy of "Ernest Ball. Songs," May 6, year and source unknown. Photocopy of "Favors Hebrew Acts" in Variety, August 26, 1910. Photocopy of "One Arrest Not Enough" in Variety, November 12, year and source unknown. Photocopy of "Artist's Contract," March 25, 1911, source unknown. Photocopy of "Publishers 'Making' Songs for Next Season's Demand," in Variety, June 1, 1912. Photocopy of "New Acts Next Week," in Variety, date unknown. Photocopy of "The Negro Players," in Variety, June 20, 1913. Photocopy of "Chance for Colored Acts," in Variety, December- 20, 1912.
  - Newspaper Advertisements: Music Publishing Companies, 1911-1912, 22
    Photocopy of an advertisement for "Five Healthy Hits" for the Ted Snyder Company, Inc. in Variety, date unknown. Photocopy of an advertisement "Again We Say…" for the Ted Snyder Company, Inc. in Variety, April 22, 1911. Photocopy of "Home Run Hits!" for the Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co., in Variety, October 11, 1912 Photocopy of an advertisement "The Hit Publishers" for the Ted Snyder Company, Inc. in Variety, November 4, 1911 (2 copies). Photocopy of an advertisement "A Few Summer Specialties" for the Ted Snyder Co., Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co., in Variety, July 26, 1912. Photocopy of an advertisement "Hit Songs by Hit Writers from Hit Publishers," for the Ted Snyder Company, Inc., December 9, 1911, source unknown. Photocopy of an advertisement "Already the Talk of the Country" for the Ted Snyder Company, Inc. in Variety, January 20, 1912. Photocopy of an advertisement "Sing Your Way to Success…" for the Ted Snyder Company, Inc. in Variety, August 19, year unknown. Photocopy of an advertisement "The Hit Mine…Alexander's Ragtime Band and After the Honeymoon" for the Ted Snyder Company, Inc. in Variety, September 23, year unknown. Photocopy of an advertisement "The Hit Mine…Mysterious Rag and When I'm Alone, I'm Lonesome" for the Ted Snyder Company, Inc. in Variety, September 23, year unknown. Photocopy of an advertisement "New Year, New Hits" in Variety, January 14, 1911. Photocopy of an advertisement "Follow the Sure Fire Firm" in Variety, November 19, year unknown. Photocopy of an advertisement "Stop! Look! Listen!" in Variety, date unknown.
  - Newspaper Clippings: Book Reviews, 1997-1999; 23
    Newspaper section, "Arts and Letters," including Ivry, Benjamin. "From 'Sadie Solome (Go Home)' to 'Easter Parade,' or How Izzy Baline Became Irving Berlin" in Forward, April 18, 1997, 9-10. Newspaper section, "Commentary," including "Irving Berlin: Melting Pot to the Very Best in U.S. Music," book review by William Hyland, in the Washington Times, April 6, 1997, B7, B8 (two copies).
  - Newspaper Clippings: Miscellaneous, 1937-1939, 24
    Photocopy of "New Acts Next Week," in Variety, June 25, year unknown. Photocopy of "Down Beat's Carl Cons to Open Off Beat Club in Chicago," January, 1939, source unknown. Photocopy of "Musicians Run By Waiters?,"date and source unknown. Photocopy of "Rhythm is Our Business,"October, 1937, source unknown. Photocopy of "Paris Listened to Duke…," August, 1937, source unknown. Newspaper clipping, "And the Band Plays on: Municipal Musicians Celebrate the Band's 75th Anniversary," by Maurer, David A. in The Daily Progress, E1, E6. Newspaper clipping of "Seen but not Heard, Artists Helped Sell the Songs," by Glatzer, Hal, in The New York Times, August 23, 1998. Photocopy of "Music for the Picture" in the Moving Picture World, October 16, 1915. Post-it note from Schubert, Linda to Hamm, Charles, April 21. Photocopy of "Record Bulletins for September 1912" in The Talking Machine World, August 15, 1912, including note from Paul (?). Photocopy of "The Friars Complimentary Dinner to Mr. Irving Berlin," October 19, 1913. The Songs of Irving Berlin. New York: Irving Berlin Music Corp.
  - "Mr. Bones", undated, 25
    Research notes. Photocopy of several pages of a play, untitled.
  - "The Missing Santa Claus" and "Keep Smiling", 1999; 26
    Sears, Benjamin and Connor, Bradford, note, signed. Photocopy of Sears, Benjamin and Bradford Connor. "The Missing Santa Claus: An Irving Berlin Mystery-Solved!" in Sheet Music Magazine, November/December 1999, 6-7, 46-47, 58-60. Marrone, Sandy to Hamm, Charles, June 18, 1999, typed letter, signed. Newspaper clipping of "Let's Face the Music," by Leithauser, Brad in The New York Review, April 22, 1999, 15-20.
  - "The Piano Bugs", 1915; 27
    Synopsis of "the Piano Bugs," from Whitcomb, 76-77. Photocopy of the handwritten transcript of "the Piano Bugs" lyrics.
  - Lyrics and Sheet Music for "Sixteen", undated, 28
    Photocopy of lyrics of "Sixteen, Sweet Sixteens," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Sixteen, Sweet Sixteens," by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Photocopy of sheet music for "Sixteen, Sweet Sixteens," by Berlin, Irving.
  - Watch Your Step, 1912-1998; 29
    New Amsterdam Theatre, New York: Frank V. Strauss & Co., February 8, 1915. Research notes, undated, 2 pages. Photocopy of "Mrs. Frank K. Clark Sings" and "Cohan's Musical Revue," source and date unknown. Research notes, undated, 1 page. Photocopy of two pages of an opera medley, unidentified. Photocopy of Smith, Harry B. "The Follies of 1912, Part 3," 1912, pgs 1-27. List of acts and Copyright Info for "Watch Your Step" at the Globe Theatre, December 8, 1914, typed, 2 copies. Photocopy of an advertisement for "Watch Your Step," December 13, 1914, source unknown, 2 copies. Photocopy of the first page of the Finale Act III, for "Watch Your Step," copyright 1914. Research notes, February 26, 1995, 3 pages. Research notes, May 27, 1994, 5 pages. Research notes, November 2, 1994, 4 pages. List of Irving Berlin Works, T-W, 2 pages, typed. Research notes, undated, 7 pages. Theater Museum Information, London, including regulations and hours, 3 pages. Receipt of Requested Title from the Theatre Museum Study Room of London, November 2, 1994. Charosh, Paul to Hamm, Charles, March 1, 1998, typed letter, signed.
  - Sheet Music and Lyrics, Post 1914, 1914-1962; 30
    Photocopy of lyrics for "Black Sheep," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics for "Jungle Ball Finale," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics for "Sunshine and Heaven's," by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Various pages of sheet music, untitled, Photocopy of lyrics for "Poor Little Rich Girls Dog," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of chorus for "How Deep is the Ocean," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of verse for "How Deep is the Ocean," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics for "How Deep is the Ocean," by Berlin, Irving, typed (three copies). Photocopy of lyrics with revisions for "How Deep is the Ocean," by Berlin, Irving, typed (two copies). Photocopy of Airline Reciept. Photocopy of lyrics for "I'm Not Afraid," by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Photocopy of sheet music for "Always," by Berlin, Irving, original lead sheet. Photocopy of sheet music for "Always," by Berlin, Irving, piano version. Photocopy of lyrics for "Song Writer's Speech," by Berlin, Irving, typed, with revisions. Photocopy of lyrics for "Song Writer's Speech," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of several pages of original sheet music for "Beefsteak Dinner."
  - Miscellaneous Song Lyrics and Sheet Music by Irving Berlin, undated, 31
    Photocopy of lyrics of "For George Gershwin," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of various lyrics, unnamed, autograph. Photocopy of lyrics of "Marching Along With Time," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Let Me Sing," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Knights of the Road," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "An Original Melody," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of "Songs in Book 1," source unknown. Photocopy of "Book No. 3," source unknown. Photocopy of "Book No. 4," source unknown. Photocopy of "Book No. 5," source unknown. Photocopy of "Book No. 6" source unknown. List of songs entitled "The Music of Irving Berlin, 1907-1914," including copyright date and no, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Treat Her Like a Baby," by Berlin, Irving, typed, (two copies). Photocopy of lyrics of "Happy Little Chorus Girl," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Oos Snooky Ookums is Oo," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "That's Just Why I Love You," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Abby Sings an Irish Song," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of sheet music for "Abby Sings an Irish Song," by Berlin, Irving. Photocopy of lyrics of "Alexander's Ragtime Band, Parody," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Alexander's Ragtime Band," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Along Came Ruth, (female double)," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Becky's Got a Job in a Musical Show," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Call Again," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of "Do It Again," by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Photocopy of lyrics of "Fiddle Dee Dee," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Going Up, Going Up, Going Up, Going Up" by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of "Furnishing a Home for Two," by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Photocopy of lyrics of "I Love to Quarrel With You (Double)" by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "I Want to Go Back to Michigan (Down on the Farm)" by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of sheet music for "I Want to Go Back to Michigan (Down on the Farm)" by Berlin, Irving. Photocopy of lyrics of "I Want to Go Back to Michigan (Down on the Farm)/Double Version" by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "I Want to Go Back to Michigan (Down on the Farm)/Double Version" by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Photocopy of lyrics of "Ike, Ike (The Yiddish Ball Player)," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of lyrics of "Ike, Ike (The Yiddish Ball Player)/Double Version," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of sheet music for "Ike, Ike (The Yiddish Ball Player)," by Berlin, Irving. Photocopy of "Keep on Walking," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of sheet music for "Kiss Your Sailor Boy Goodbye," by Berlin, Irving. Photocopy of "Lock Me in Your Harem," by Berlin, Irving, typed/autograph. Photocopy of "Ragtime Jockey Man," by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Photocopy of "Ragtime Jockey Man (Conversation)," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of "Ragtime Soldier Man," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of "Ragtime Soldier Man," by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Photocopy of sheet music for "I'm San Francisco Bound," by Berlin, Irving. Photocopy of sheet music for "Choo Choo Bound," by Berlin, Irving. Photocopy of "Oozums Little Snoozums is Oo," by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Photocopy of "Oozums Little Snoozums is OO, OO, OO?" by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of "That's My Idea of Paradise," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of "When Johnson's Quartet's Harmonize," by Berlin, Irving, autograph. Photocopy of various songs, untitled, autograph. Photocopy of "You Picked a Bad Day Out to Say Good Bye," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of sheet music for "Bad Day," by Berlin, Irving. Photocopy of "You've Got Your Mother's Big Blue Eyes," by Berlin, Irving, typed. Photocopy of sheet music for "You've Got Your Mother's Big Blue Eyes," by Berlin, Irving. "Irving Berlin List of songs, entitled "List of Songs, In Berlin's Hand," typed. List of songs, written "In Berlin's Hand," autograph. Photocopy of the lyrics for "Pickaninny Mose," by Berlin, Irving. Photocopy of songlists.
  - Miscellaneous Sheet Music, undated, 32
    Harris, Chas. K. "A Rabbi's Daughter," arranged by Jos. Clauder. Photocopy of Berlin, Irving, Arthur Wimperis and Hartly Carrick. "Keep Smiling." Photocopy of Meyer, Geo W. and Joe Gershwin. "Brass Band Ephraham Jones." Photocopy of Greene & Werner. "Ephraham Johnson: Don't Live Here No More." Photocopy of Couch, F. N. "Kathleen Mavourneen." Photocopy of Berlin, Irving. "Simple Melody," from Watch Your Step. Photocopy of Berlin, Irving. "The Freedom Train." Photocopy of various pages from "the "Cocoanuts," by Berlin, Irving Photocopy of Berlin, Irving. "The Syncopated Walk." Photocopy of Gasdorf, Alfred. "Sic'em Prinz." Photocopy of Graham, George W. "When Alexanders Ragtime Band Plays 'Over There.'" Photocopy of the title pages and incomplete sheet music for Berlin, Irving, "Alexander's Ragtime Band: Two Step," "Everybody's Doing it Now," "He's a Rag Picker," "I Want to Go Back to Michigan (two versions)," "Rag-time Violin," "When that Midnight Choo, Choo, leaves for Alabama." Photocopy of sheet music for Berlin, Irving, "Santa Claus: A Syncopated Christmas Song." Photocopy of sheet music for Kern, Jerome, "A Jazz Christmas Carol." Photocopy of sheet music for Berlin, Irving, "Down on Uncle Jerry's Farm." Photocopy of sheet music for Braham, Dave and Harrigan, Ed. "McNally's Row of Flats." Photocopy of title page, Berlin, Irving, "Do your Duty Doctor and Cure my Pain." Photocopy of title page, Abraham, Maurice and Berlin, Irving, "Queenie." Photocopy of title page, Snyder, Ted and Berlin, Irving, "Sweet Italian Love." Photocopy of Drama, "We're all Going to College, Boys. Rah! Rah! Rah!"
  - Discography from the Irving Berlin Music Company: Part 1, pgs 2-143, undated, 33
    Irving Berlin Discography from the Irving Berlin Music Company, 2-243.
  - Discography from the Irving Berlin Music Company: Part 1, pgs 144-end, undated, 34
    Irving Berlin Discography from the Irving Berlin Music Company, 2-259, including 2 attachments.
  - Sheet Music Exchange "Irving Berlin Catalogue", 1990; 35
    Motto, Vincent, "The Irving Berlin Catalog," in Sheet Music Exchange, 8/1, February 1990.
  - Miscellaneous Songs Listings of Irving Berlin, undated, 36
    Photocopy of "Musical Compositions Registered by Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co.," List of Berlin tunes, typed. Photocopy of "Musical Compositions Registered by Ted Snyder Co.," List of Berlin tunes, typed. Photocopy of song lists, Irving Berlin Master Song Series, "Sweet Italian Love." Photocopy of Jay, Dave, "The Irving Berlin Songography: 1907-1966," New York, Arlington House, 7-31.
  - Program Notes for "Louisiana Purchase", 1997; 37
    Program for Louisiana Purchase, by the New London Barn Playhouse, June-July 1997.
  - "Wall to Wall Irving Berlin" Performance, 1994; 38
    Cossa, Joanne, Miller, Alan, Sheffer, Isaiah (members of the board of directors for Symphony Space) to Hamm, Charles, April 19, 1994, typed letter, signed. Program for "Wall to Wall Irving Berlin" performed at the Symphony Space, New York. March 19, 1994. (5 copies) Magazine advertisement of "Wall to Wall Irving Berlin." Magazine information not provided, undated. 4. Holden, Stephen. "Marathon for a Master of the Popular Song." Review. The New York Times. March 21, 1994. Newspaper clipping. Advertisement for "Wall to Wall Irving Berlin." Newspaper information not provided, March 18, 1994, original and three copies.
  - "'Alexander's Ragtime Band' and the Real Story of Irving Berlin," in Life, 1938; 39
    Life, issue August 15, 1938, includes articles, "Old Berlin Hits make 'Alexander's Ragtime Band'" and "This is Berlin's Real Story."
  - "Blue Skies" by Jeffrey Magee, 2000; 40
    Magee, Jeffrey, "Irving Berlin's "Blue Skies": Ethnic Affiliations and Musical Transformations." Music Quarterly, 84/4 (Winter 2000), 537-580. Magee, Jeffrey, "Blue Skies": The Ethnic Affiliations, Narrative Functions, and Musical Transformations of an American Song," draft.
  - "Gambling with Chromaticism?" by David Carson Berry, 2000, 41
    Berry, David Carson. "Gambling with Chromaticism? Extra-Diatonic Melodic Expression in the Songs of Irving Berlin," unpublished paper, 2000
  - "Jewish Music and the Profit Motive," by Andrew Killick, 1996; 42
    Killick, Andrew P. to Middleton, Richard, March 29, 1996, typed letter, signed. Killick, Andrew. "'Jewish Music' and the Profit Motive in Popular Music and Musicals, 1960-1976: Can Music Encode the Unspeakable?" Revised paper submitted to the journal Popular Music. February 3, 1996.
  - Music of the United States of America (MUSA) Proposal, 1995; 43
    Receipt of Complimentary volumes of MUSA, V. 2, Parts, 1, 2, and 3 from A-R Editions, Inc. to Charles Hamm, dated January 12, 1995. Hamm, Charles. "The Songs of Irving Berlin, 1907-1914." Research Proposal to MUSA, undated.
  - "The Secret of Song Writing" by Nathan Caspar, undated, 44
    Photocopy of "The Secret of Song Writing," by Nathan, Casper, undated. Photocopy of an advertisement for Casper Nathan, date and source unknown.
  - Photographs: Berlin, undated, 45
    Various photocopies of photographs of Berlin, Irving.
  - Photographs/Negatives: Berlin and Sheet Music, undated, 46
    Photographs of the title pages of "Alexander's Ragtime Band, Two-Step' and "Alexander's Ragtime Band." Photograph of Irving Berlin (including negative) Photograph of title page: "The Dance of the Grizzly Bear," by Berlin, Irving (including negative). Photograph of title page: "Dreams Just Dreams (including negative). Photograph of title page: Alexander's Ragtime Band Two-Step (including negative).
  - Walton, Robin to Hamm, Charles, typed letter, signed, 1994-05-09
  - Hamm, Charles to Chapin, Theodore S., typed letter, unsigned, 1994-05-06
  - Chapin, Theodore S. to Hamm, Charles, typed letter, signed, 1994-04-18
  - Walton, Robin to Hamm, Charles, typed letter, signed, 1994-04-26
  - Hamm, Charles to Walton, Robin, typed letter, unsigned, 1994-05-01
  - Chapin, Theodore S. to Hamm, Charles, typed letter, signed, 1994-07-30
  - Post-it note, Robin Walton, $500, undated
  - Hamm, Charles to Chapin, Theodore S., typed letter, unsigned, 1994-03-21
  - Research notes, undated
  - Hamm, Charles to Chapin, Theodore S., typed letter, unsigned, 1994-01-01
  - Hamm, Charles. "Irving Berlin's Early Songs as Biographical Documents." Music Quarterly, 77/1, 10-34 (two copies), Spring 1993
  - Hamm, Charles to Chapin, Theodore S., typed letter, unsigned, 1994-03-07
  - Gillette, Nicole to Hamm, Charles, typed letter, signed, 1992-11-16
  - Hamm, Charles to Chapin, Theodore S., typed letter, unsigned, 1993-03-17
  - Schneider, Hilda to Charles Hamm, typed letter, signed, 1992-10-09
  - "The Irving Berlin Collection," Library of Congress Information Bulletin. 51/23, 1992-11-03
  - Peters, Alton to Hamm, Charles, typed letter, signed, 1992-11-09
  - List of Berlin tunes, undated
  - "The Songs of Irving Berlin, 1907-1914"
  - Critical notes and corrections for two songs: "At the Devil's Ball" and "How Can You Love Such a Man," undated
  - Terms and Conditions of Agreement, Vincent Scuderi to American Musicological Society, incomplete, undated
  - Hamm, Charles to Griggs, Flora, typed letter, unsigned, 1996-07-31
  - Green, Lucy, to Hamm Charles, typed letter, signed, 1996-04-30
  - Hamm, Charles to Barrett, Mary Ellin, Emmet Linda, Peters, Elizabeth, Kimball, Robert, and Fink, Bert, typed letter, unsigned, 1996-06-17
  - Hamm, Charles to Griggs, Flora, typed letter, unsigned, 1996-09-11
  - Griggs, Flora, to Hamm, Charles, typed letter, signed, 1996-08-22